

# **AKIS GAZEPIDIS**

DATA SCIENTIST

## PROFILE

Data Scientist with experience in information extraction techniques used on documents, building ETL pipelines and training of machine learning models. My passion is to accelerate internal company processes with custom made cloud applications wich lead to datadriven decisions.

## CONTACT

+30 6986777430

<u>akisgazepidis@gmail.com</u>

in LinkedIn Profile

Personal Portfolio

Google Certifications Profile

Microsoft Certifications Profile

<u>Databricks Certifications Profile</u>

## HARD SKILLS

- Python
- PySpark
- Git
- Databricks
- Snowflake
- Azure
- PostgreSQL
- Azure SQL server
- Power Bi
- APIs
- Docker
- CI/CD
- MongoDB

### EXPERIENCE

#### **DATA ENGINEERING CONSULTANT**

#### D-ONE

Apr 2023- Present

- · Create ETL pipelines to process data with automated jobs.
- Build, test and deploy tables into database systems.
- Interact with APIs for data collection.

**Project:** Participate in database Integration projects in sports, pharmaceutical and technology sectors

### **DATA SCIENTIST**

#### <u>Generali</u>

Jan 2022- Apr 2023

- Integrate Bitbucket version control system in development.
- · Consolidate data with the use of APIs.
- Integrate OCR, Machine Vision & Machine Learning fields to automated processes.

### JUNIOR DATA SCIENTIST

Big Blue Data Academy

Apr 2021 - Sep 2021

- · Web scraping with Beautiful Soup, Requests & Selenium.
- · Create embeddings from texts.

**Project:** Build a content based recommendation system for active jobs depending on a CV input.

## SOFT SKILLS

- Problem Solving
- · Critical Thinking
- Adaptability
- Team Working

## LANGUAGES

Greek - Native

English - ILTES 6.5

## PORTFOLIO

**Data Pipeline Optimization** 

Optimization of Titan's Mill

<u>Deep Learning - loan prediction</u>

<u>Classcentral scraper</u>

**Image Handwritting Recognition** 

NLP - Climate Change IR System

### EDUCATION

### **WORKSHOPS - CERTIFICATIONS**

Databricks - Associate Developer Spark - Apr 2024

GCP - Generative AI for ML Engineers - Dec 2023

Microsoft - Data Analyst Associate - Aug 2023

**D-ONE** - BigQuery Essentials - Nov 2023

#### **MASTER OF SCIENCE**

<u>American College of Greece</u> - <u>Data Science</u> 2022 - 2024

#### **BACHELOR OF SCIENCE**

<u>University of Piraeus</u> - <u>Statistics & Insurance</u> 2011 - 2020

### DATA SCIENCE BOOTCAMP 500 HOURS HANDS-ON

**Big Blue Data Academy** 

Sep 2021 - Dec 2021

- Databases (SQL, MongoDB), APIs & Web Scraping
- EDA & Data Cleaning (Pandas, Numpy, Regex)
- Big Data (PySpark) & Cloud Computing (Amazon Web Services)
- Machine Learning (Scikit Learn) & Deep Learning (Keras)
- · Visualization (Matplotlib, Seaborn, Dash, PowerBi)

# DATA SCIENCE ACADEMY 100 HOURS HANDS-ON

Regeneration Academy by TITAN - Code.Hub

Dec 2020 - Jan 2021